SHANTHI ACHARYA

Senior UX & Interaction Designer

shanthi.s.acharya@gmail.com | 510-226-7914

Talented senior designer of user-experience design with the proven know-how to combine creativity, end user focus and business goals resulting in world-class design solutions.

10+ years of success delivering compelling user experience across web and mobile solution for enterprise and consumer brands. Experienced working in agile environments applying design-thinking, rapid prototyping approaches and collaborating with global stakeholders.

WORK EXPERIENCE

GE Global Research | Lead Interaction Designer | May 2012 - Present

Lead design & research efforts with multi disciplinary and international teams to deliver compelling user experiences for Industrial Internet Applications for 10 + projects across several GE businesses.

- o **Industrial eCommerce**: Developed UX strategy and assets for My Industrial Store, an ecommerce platform that can be leveraged across GE businesses. Lead the design efforts producing wireframes, design patterns and interactive HTML5 prototype.
- Field Service UX: Envisioned and prototyped an iOS app that allows field engineers to capture a machine
 part picture and submit a part request to speed up the parts ordering process for GE Power Conversion
 business.
- o **Fleet Management**: Lead UX strategy for Oil & Gas Fleet solution that provided a holistic view of the customer assets and alarms using web & mobile cloud solutions. Worked with Agile development team and successfully delivered designs for sprints ahead of time
- O Controls Convergence UX: Developed UX strategy, storyboards and wireframes that provides field service engineers with a mobile solution in their workflow of commissioning an Oil & Gas site. This represented a leap forward for GE by increasing the interoperability of GE's controls platform and providing a modern, higher quality user experience.
- PlantWorks: Lead UX strategy & research efforts for controls developer integrated tools suite that
 accelerate plant solutions from design through commissioning. Applied GE Fastwork approach
 with rapid iterative cycle working with several GE business by conducting workshops and
 interviews. Delivered journey maps, storyboards and interactive wireframes for a compelling
 design solution.
- Next Generation HMI: Working on Research and Design efforts for revamping the HMI SCADA authoring tool and operator experiences to provide situational awareness, collaboration and real time operational intelligence.

Western Digital | Senior UX Designer | Jun 2010 - May2012

Lead designer for 5+ projects at Western Digital Branded Products Group to deliver innovative design solutions for WD networked devices.

WD Media Library: Delivered Information architecture, task flows, wireframes and interactive Flex
prototype for rich media web UI for WD home storage devices. Established UCD process in the team
and guided the user researcher on usability study. Worked with Agile development team to deliver
designs and coded the front end for several areas.

- WD TV: Designed screens and interactions for WD TV Live Hub media player to integrate with Mobile devices. Delivered task flows and UI specs and worked with product management and engineering to ensure best user experience.
- WD Mobile Apps: Created and refined UI screens for WD Photos, a photo viewer app available in iTunes App store and Android market. Included several usability fixes for existing UI and created interactions and mockups for new features. Created concepts for WD 2 go mobile app, a file browser to view contents from networked devices.
- WD Personal Cloud: Created flows and wireframes for WD 2go.com, a web based portal that provides easy remote access to WD networked devices. Designed screens and interaction for remote access integration and worked with several product teams to integrate this central feature for WD personal cloud products.

UX Consultant | Nov 2009 - May 2010

- Kno Inc: Translated concepts and wireframes into prototype requirements and technology selection. Created production quality interactive prototype for touch screen based tablet device targeted at education market using Adobe Flex. Worked with user researchers in planning and conducting usability studies with the prototype and provided design feedback to the team.
- o **ContextTV**: Designed flows and wireframes for contexTV video platform and worked with cross team.

IBM | UX Designer Intern | Mar 2008 - Oct 2009

o **IBM Mashup Center**: Worked on Design & Usability testing of IBM Mashup Center Catalog to provide better integration experience across different components of Mashup center. Delivered mockups and an interactive Adobe Flex prototype. Conducted usability testing and presented usability findings to key stakeholders and worked with developers to fix the usability issues.

Intel | Senior Software Engineer | Mar 2008 - Oct 1999

- User Experience Assessment: Designed and conducted tests with participants to evaluate Gaming experience on various systems. Designed and implemented a tool using C# .Net to provide Gaming Experience rating based on the statistical model.
- O Application Performance Assessment: Created proof points to showcase Intel architecture advantage on various multimedia applications (3dsmax, Photoshop Elements, Sound Forge, and Windows Media Encoder) and office productivity applications (MS Excel 2007 Multithreading) based on user tasks and usage model that were used in marketing collaterals and the technical press. Design, implementation and maintenance of Mobile technology (MobileMark 2005) and Internet performance technology (WebMark 2004 and WebMark 2001) development with main focus on providing support for BAPCo (an industry consortium).

Education:

M.S. Human Factors, San Jose State University. 2009

M.S. Computer Science, California State University, Hayward .1999